

COMPUTER SCIENCE PHD STUDENT · RUTGERS, NEW BRUNSWICK

A2, Seethalakshmi Flats, No 32, Patel Street, Nehru Nagar, Chromepet, Tamil Nadu - 600044.

🛘 (+91) 9677059650 | 🔀 krishnan.gosakan@rutgers.edu | 🏕 krishnangosakan.github.io/KrishnanGosakan | 🖸 KrishnanGosakan

Summary

A software engineer and researcher with 6 years of professional software development experience. My area of interest is in computer systems, ranging from compilers to system security. I am specializing on operating systems and computer architecture for my PhD research, with concentration in memory subsystem. I am switching to academia, after 6 years of professional experience, to pursue my doctorate in computer science. I am a logical thinker and analytical in nature. I learn things quickly. I am looking forward for a research career, where I wish to improve user applications and operating systems for next generation computer architecture.

Education

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey

New Brunswick, New Jersey

Aug. 2023

DOCTORATE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

- Advisor: Prof. Sudarsun Kannan
- · Working on a multi institute collaborative project on improving virtual memory for next-generation processors
- My contribution deals with improving TLB efficiency by reducing it's miss rate
- Implemented the idea in gem5 architectural simulator
- Evaluating the design against workloads like graph500, XSBench, BTree

Sri Sivasubramaniya Nadar College of Engineering

Kalavakkam, Tamil Nadu

Aug. 2012 - July. 2016

B.Tech in Information Technology

- · Final year project:Inter-video comparison for redundancy identification using python and mongodb database
- · Project Advisor: Prof. E.M. Malathy
- Implemented a File Management System using Front-end as java and Backend as oracle database as a mini academic project
- · Created a Banking Account Creation and Management software using Java as front-end and MySQL as back-end
- First prize in programming contest in SSN EEE symposium

Smt Ramkuwar Devi Fomra Vivekananda Vidyalaya

Chromepet, Tamil Nadu

July. 2012

HIGHER SECONDARY, 12TH

- Board: Tamil Nadu State Board
- Subjects: Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Biology

Smt Ramkuwar Devi Fomra Vivekananda Vidyalaya

Chromepet, Tamil Nadu

May. 2010

- SECONDARY SCHOOL, 10TH
- Board: Central Board of Secondary Education (CBSE)
- Subjects: Mathematics, Science, Social
- Participated in various science quizzes
- Extracurricular Activities: Chess, Yoga

Publication

Mosaic Pages: Big TLB Reach with Small Pages

ASPLOS 2023

- Contributed to architectural simulation part of the paper
- Improved TLB reach by reducing it's miss rate for next-generation computer architectures.
- Awarded Distinguished Research Paper

Work Experience _____

KLA - Tencor Chennai

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Sept. 2022 - Nov. 2022

· Worked on Surfscan Image Analysis Cluster

- Improved the product by making use of huge pages
- Demonstrated better memory management policy for the product

June 15, 2023 Krishnan Gosakan · Résumé

Zoho Corporation Chennai

MEMBER TECHNICAL STAFF Feb. 2017 - July. 2022

- Worked as a C++ developer for Zoho Assist native Windows application and installer
- · Responsible for design, implementation, testing and customer support for Zoho Assist service and deployment components
- Module owner of Windows Deployment for Zoho Assist Unattended Installer
- Have experience in Microsoft GPO and Intune deployment technologies
- Worked on building an MSI based installer for Zoho Assist Unattended Support
- Developed a C# application for bulk deployment of Zoho Assist Unattended support InstallShield-based installer in domain or workgroup based windows network.
- Designed and developed a load testing framework for Zoho Assist
- · Designed and developed version update system with failure detection using MD5 hash for Zoho Assist
- Reported SQL injection and XSS bugs in multiple Zoho products
- · Reported privilege escalation and injection based security issues in Zoho Assist as a part of HackFox internal security hackathon

Cognizant Chennai

• Trained on Mainframe Technology and Cobol programming language

- Worked on IBM Z mainframe systems • Awarded as the Best Student of the Batch